<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>scanner on Mathis Gauthey's Website</title><link>https://mathisgauthey.github.io/mathisgauthey.github.io_old/tags/scanner/</link><description>Recent content in scanner on Mathis Gauthey's Website</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 07:41:25 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mathisgauthey.github.io/mathisgauthey.github.io_old/tags/scanner/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Best Android Scanner App for 2021 in My Opinion</title><link>https://mathisgauthey.github.io/mathisgauthey.github.io_old/the-best-android-scanner-app-for-2021-in-my-opinion/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 07:41:25 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://mathisgauthey.github.io/mathisgauthey.github.io_old/the-best-android-scanner-app-for-2021-in-my-opinion/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="the-best-android-scanner-app-for-2021-in-my-opinion">The Best Android Scanner App for 2021 in My Opinion&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Hi everyone, good morning from France o/&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I spent 2 hours yesterday testing android apps from these two links :&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Android/comments/elxi9x/reviews_best_document_scanner_apps_for_android/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>https://www.reddit.com/r/Android/comments/elxi9x/reviews_best_document_scanner_apps_for_android/&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/androidapps/comments/d06zmg/after_camscanner_malware_mess_i_went_on_a_quest/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>https://www.reddit.com/r/androidapps/comments/d06zmg/after_camscanner_malware_mess_i_went_on_a_quest/&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>They are a bit outdated (1 year ago) so I decided to give it a shot.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I won&amp;rsquo;t go far in my explanation but what I was looking for was :&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Free or small one time purchase (NO SUBSCRIPTION)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Automatic Google Drive Sync&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Very good color and B/W quality for printing handwritten notes as a student&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Batch scan with the ability (like Camscanner) to resize images fast and to change the filter easily&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fast to boot&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Good autocrop feature&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>I decided not to care about OCR but the tools I chose are quite good from what I heard in Reddit and the comment section.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here is my TOP 3 with my phone (Xiaomi Mi A2 Lite with a pretty bad camera)&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Notebloc (or ClearScan which is basically the same app, take the one with the lowest price)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>SwiftScan (former Scanbot)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>GeniusScan&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Why ? Notebloc is basically Camscanner for free with amazing image quality and Google Drive Sync. 3.59€ wasn&amp;rsquo;t much, I don&amp;rsquo;t have anything else to say, it is amazing and most importantly : Fast to scan, resize and change the filter.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Swiftscan offered good image quality while being quite slow before. Now I don&amp;rsquo;t have a good image quality since the few last updates, but I know it&amp;rsquo;s related to my phone and the support is going to help about that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Same quality as far as I tested it out (used it for the last 2 years) but it is slower in scanning, resizing and especially in changing filter. It might be related to my phone, but if my phone can be that fast in Notebloc, it means it should be the same for everyone as my phone is not a standard in speed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Finally we have GeniusScan. I&amp;rsquo;ll have to admit, I like the fact that this is a French company developping it. But I took it for his precise autocrop and his quality. But it wasn&amp;rsquo;t as good as the other two even if he was fast, but in the end we do want great filter quality and pdf quality, so I decided not to put him before.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s it, if you want to make your own opinion about that, you can check the two links I dropped at the beginning of this post.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>TL : DR :&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Notebloc : Good quality and amazingly fast&lt;/p>
&lt;p>SwiftScan : Good quality but now has problems with my phones and some other, slower because of optimization andbecause of the way features are implemented&lt;/p>
&lt;p>GeniusScan : Amazingly fast with good autocrop but can&amp;rsquo;t compete with scan quality of the other two&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Have a wonderful day, stay safe everyone o/&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>